www.CharlesGrogan.com www.linkedin.com/in/charles-grogan/

Professional Summary

Outgoing and experienced professional with 7+ years of management experience specializing in team management and strategic planning. Seeking to leverage servant leadership abilities and expertise to have a successful career in web development. Talents and skills include time management, critical inquiry and problem solving, and adaptability in rapidly changing environments that will prove essential as a successful web developer.

Technical Skills

Client-Side Skills		Server-Side Skills	
• HTML	• Git	• Ruby	• JSON
• jQuery	• CSS	• Node.js	• Firebase
• JavaScript	• React.js	• Express.js	 Mongoose
Materialize framework	• Bulma framework	• Ruby on Rails	 Mongo Database
Heroku Deployment	• Bootstrap framework	• RESTful API	 MySQL (Sequelize)

Projects

Virtual Hostel - Full Stack Application

Project Manager, Lead Design & Development

Virtual Hostel is designed for travelers to share their experiences with words and photos to a community of global travelers

• **Technologies**: React.js, Mongo database, Mongoose, RESTful API, JavaScript, jQuery, Bulma CSS framework, Passport login-in, Ajax, Axios, Git, HTML, & Heroku

Campaign Query - Full Sack Application

Project Manager, Lead Developer

Campaign Query uses data visualizations to showcase campaign finance contributions from the 2016 election cycle

• **Technologies:** Node.js, Express.js, JavaScript, jQuery, amCharts, High Charts, MySQL, Sequelize, APIs, Ajax, CSS, HTML, Git, & Heroku

appDoption - Full Stack Application

Product Manager – Lead Developer

appDoption was built on the concept of love at first sight + every pet needs a forever home, regardless of age

• **Technologies:** JavaScript, jQuery, RESTful APIs (Petfinder API & HERE location API), Firebase database system, Materialize CSS framework, Git, & HTML

Friend Finder - Full Stack Application

Sole Developer

Friend Finder uses a sorting algorithm to pair matches based on survey results, as compared to other survey participants

• **Technologies:** Express.js, Node.js, JSON, RESTful API, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap front-end framework, CSS, HTML, & Heroku

SimpleBlog - Full Stack Application - Create, Read, Update, Delete

Sole Developer

SimpleBlog is a CRUD application that stores blog messages, enables comments, and secure log-in feature

Technologies: Ruby on Rails, Ruby, SASS, Bootstrap front-end framework, HTML, & Heroku

<u>bAmazon</u> – Node.js Application

Sole Developer

bAmazon is a simulated store front application that tracks inventory and calculates price based on the quantity purchased

Technologies: Node.js, NPM Inquirer, MySQL, NPM MySQL, Cli-Tables2

NYT Web Scraper - Full Stack Application

Sole Developer

NYT Web Scraper is designed to search the archives at the New York Times and return stories pertaining to query

• Technologies: JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax, API, Bootstrap front-end framework, CSS, & HTML

Experience

Sales Consultant, Enterprise Holdings Chicago, Illinois

October 2015 – June 2018

- Produced at 132% of my goal last quarter and 127% YTD, regarding sales and leads produced by my portfolio of accounts: credit union and strategic partners combined
- Strong analytical skills to track current methods and trends to create new strategies focusing on client retention, referral metrics, and 100% saturation into accounts
- Thrive on developing creative and strategic solutions, troubleshooting, and determining the root issue for my customers and accounts to drive revenue, customer satisfaction, and brand loyalty
- Consistently seeking to create and maintain positive strategic partnerships across internal and external stakeholders, including senior leadership and key contacts to push new initiatives
- Lead product presentations, Q&A sessions, and post-sale follow-ups monthly
- Utilize and implement a needs-based, consultative sales method, and GAP analysis
- Proficient in Salesforce and Microsoft Suite with the ability to train others, navigate and analysis data

Branch Manager, Enterprise Holdings Chicago, Illinois

February 2013 – October 2015

- Managed book of business consisting of nearly 70 national and local accounts, developed strategies to create growth, retention, and 100% business saturation
- Responsible for professional and personal advancement of nearly forty management trainees. Conducted weekly and monthly sales trainings, and created a positive work environment
- Grew branch's fleet by approximately 40% over previous year (130 to 180 over 12 months) which was 30% above my goal achieved through personal credibility, follow through and follow up
- Increased branch profit by 80% in same period (\$95K to \$171K in total profit dollars) which was 60% above my goal credit to building strong relationships and strategic planning
- Supervisor of multiple locations, including O'Hare International Airport where I was responsible for nearly 125 full time and part time personalities, requests, motivators, and stressors

General Manager, Union Station Restaurant Harrisonburg, Virginia

June 2010 – August 2012

- Oversaw the day to day operations of a two-hundred fifty seat restaurant with sales in excess \$2 million per year
- Created a positive, competitive, and thriving work environment through employee engagement, high levels of enthusiasm, and regular coaching / performance sessions
- Strong ability to effectively multitask especially in a fast-paced work environment

Education

Northwestern University – School of Professional Studies Full Stack (MERN) Web Development Coding Boot Camp

Graduated - October 2018

Ohio University – College of Health and Human Services Bachelor of Science in Human and Consumer Sciences

Graduated - June 2010